In this video, we're going to talk about
entering in general journals in Dynamics
SL and compare that to the experience of
entering in those same transactions in
Business Central.
To begin, let's go to SL where I have
already created a GL batch and entered
in two different general journal
entries.
The first entry is for a monthly auto
insurance bill for a small fleet of
company vehicles.
I can see the reference number,
description, as well as the accounts
being debited and credited.
In this same batch, I have also entered
in a transaction for our monthly
interest income on our savings account.
I could continue to enter in more
journal entries and when complete, post
the batch.
Now, let's look at Business Central and
see how we can enter in those same
journal entries. To begin, I'll navigate
to the general journal window.
This is where we can create and define
batches for our journal entries.
In this example, the batches are set up
operationally, but you could create
batches per user if you had multiple
users entering in transactions
onto general ledger.
For our purpose, I'll go ahead and
select the default batch.
In the general journal, you can see much
of the same information you did in SL.
Let's enter in the auto insurance
journal entry we saw in SL.
I don't always remember the account
number, so I can start typing the name
of the account and then the drop down
will automatically filter for me.
I can update the description or
references if I want more detail and
then finish filling out the rest of the
journal entry with the correct debit
amount and account being credited.
Next, I can select
to create a new document and enter in
the interest income journal entry.
However, instead of entering the next
journal entry the same as we just did,
let's look at another way you can enter
in journal entries in Business Central.
Select the show more columns to get a
slightly different view of how you can
enter in journal entries.
You can see it's showing my first
document as two lines in the grid with
my debit and credit amounts. You can
also enter in the journal entry in a
single line.
Let's do that for the interest income.
You can see how it automatically filled
in the document number for me and I can
start entering in the savings account
and of the interest earned.
Next, I can enter in the offset account
that will automatically be credited.
And this is an example of a quick and
efficient way to enter in a lot of
journal entries all at once.
Lastly, if you do have a large journal
entry, you can also choose to edit in
Excel, make the changes, and publish
those back to Business Central.
Once the information is populated in
Excel, I can easily make mass changes if
I had a large number of lines. I could
copy the lines and then edit them.
In our example, I'll go ahead and
illustrate how to make a change and push
that back into Business Central.
Now that the change has been published,
we'll go back into Business Central and
refresh the screen to see the changes.
Upon refreshing, I can see that my
amount has now been updated to $300.
Once all the journal entries are
entered, I can select to post them.
And that's a quick look at how you can
easily and effectively enter in journal
entries in Business Central.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.